#### Contact

+919911040725 (Mobile) kewallalit@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/lalit-kumarb72482104 (LinkedIn) transysco.in (Company)

### Top Skills

Science

R&D

**Embedded Linux** 

#### Certifications

Implementation Training on Quality Management System

Microsoft Certified Professional

#### Honors-Awards

Aegis Graham Bell Award 2016

#### **Publications**

RFID Based Road Transport Management System

Design & Development of Small Linux Operating System for Digital Set Top Box

RFID BASED VIRTUAL LABORATORY

Design & Development of Low Cost UHF RFID Reader

#### **Patents**

RFID BASED VIRTUAL LABORATORY

HYBRID ELECTRIC VEHICLE DUAL POWER TRANSMISSION SWITCH

HYBRID ELECTRIC SMART CAR

ELECTRIC DRIVE AUTOMATIC GULL-WING DOOR SYSTEM FOR PIXY SMART CAR

# Lalit Kumar

Inventor & Developer PIXY Hybrid Electric Smart Car Delhi

## Summary

Please don't see my skills... See my Attitude my passion.

Lalit Kumar is a research oriented design executive with proven experience in solving complex design challenges, who is comfortable in small and large business environments and a collaborative team player who is willed to roll up his sleeves to work with parties across all levels & disciplines to make a difference.

With 12+ yrs of experience in R&D of Electro-Mechanical Design, Concept Design, Embedded Systems, Computers, Electronics, System Design & Integration, RFID & Telecommunication. He designed and developed an Android Based Hybrid Electric Smart Car named as PIXY from scratch and worked on all its modules like Mechanical parts, Chassis Architecture, Electrical wiring, Sensor based Electronics systems, Android Software, Interior & Exterior design. He just completed PIXY Project in a small period of eight months.

Further, He continuing his R&D in future technologies like Magnetic Engines, Internet of Automobile (IoA), Connected Vehicles, Sensor based systems with artificial intelligence and much more.

for more info
Google "PIXY Smart Car"
www.transysco.in
E mail at kewallalit@gmail.com
Mobile +91 9911040725

## Experience

Transysco
Founder & CEO
February 2015 - Present (5 years 7 months)
North East Delhi, Delhi, India

The PIXY Hybrid Electric Smart Car.

CDAC, Noida

9 years 8 months

Sr. Project Engineer (Scientist C)
July 2010 - January 2015 (4 years 7 months)

Noida Area, India

Worked as Project Leader, RFID Technology, Embedded system, Embedded Linux, UHF RFID systems, Antenna Technology.

Project Engineer (Scientist B)

June 2006 - July 2010 (4 years 2 months)

Noida Area, India

Worked as Team Leader on RFID Technology, Embedded Linux, Designed & Developed UHF RFID Reader.

**Project Trainee** 

June 2005 - May 2006 (1 year)

Noida Area, India

Worked on Embedded Linux, Digital Video Broadcasting, Designed and Developed Linux based Digital Set Top Box.

Bharat Electronics Limited
Graduate Engineer Trainee
September 2004 - May 2005 (9 months)

Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh, India

Worked on Environment and SONAR Simulation and RADAR Technology

## Education

Dr. B. R. Ambedkar University, Agra

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Computer Science · (1999 - 2003)

KRISHNA INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY, GHAZIABAD

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Computer Science · (1999 - 2003)

Central Board of Secondary Education

All India Senior School Certificate Examination, Science · (1997 - 1998)

Central Board of Secondary Education

10th Standard, Science · (1993 - 1994)